Guide to the Locus Science Fiction Foundation archives, 1942-2012 RL.11689
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Locus Science Fiction Foundation archives
1942-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Locus Science Fiction Foundation
RL.11689
10 Linear Feet
Locus, the Magazine of the Science Fiction & Fantasy Field, was co-founded by Charles N. Brown (1937-2009), Ed Meskys (1936-), and Dave Vanderwerf (1944-) in New York in 1968. It first began as a science-fiction and fantasy one-sheet news fanzine that was created to help the Boston Science Fiction Group win its 1971 Worldcon bid. Vanderwerf left after issue #4, and Meskys after #11. Charles Brown remained as editor until his death in 2009. The Locus Archives include names files for more than 800 people, many of whom are writers, editors, or publishers. The files contain correspondence, clippings, obituaries, and writings, the bulk of which relate to American writers, though there are several files kept on writers and fans from across the world, including China, Japan, and Russia. Much of the correspondence is about publishing news, corrections, and deaths in the science-fiction, fantasy, and horror community. There are several well-known correspondents including: Poul Anderson, Isaac Asimov, Jim Baen, Ian and Betty Ballantine, Algis Budrys, Octavia E. Butler, Arthur C. Clarke, L. Sprague de Camp, Harlan Ellison, Robert Heinlein, Ursula K. Le Guin, Dean Koontz, Andre Alice Norton, James Tiptree, Jr. (Alice Sheldon), and Gene Wolfe.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by name.
Biographical / Historical
Locus, the Magazine of the Science Fiction & Fantasy Field, was co-founded by Charles N. Brown (1937-2009), Ed Meskys (1936-), and Dave Vanderwerf (1944-) in New York in 1968. It first began as a science-fiction and fantasy one-sheet news fanzine that was created to help the Boston Science Fiction Group win its 1971 Worldcon bid. Vanderwerf left after issue #4, and Meskys after #11. Charles Brown remained as editor until his death in 2009. His first wife Marsha Elkin Brown (later Marsha Jones) was co-editor from 1968-69, and his second wife Dena Benatan Brown was co-editor from 1970-77. In 1972 Charles Brown and the magazine relocated to the Bay Area in California. After his death, the magazine became owned by The Locus Science Fiction Foundation (LSFF), which is a registered 501(c)3 nonprofit dedicated to the promotion and preservation of science fiction, fantasy, and horror. Its central activity is the publication of Locus and its website Locus Online. LSFF is also responsible for the annual Locus Awards, first presented in 1971, to recognize excellence in science-fiction and fantasy literature. The magazine has won many Hugo awards.
Charles N. Brown (1937-2009) was a writer, editor, and science-fiction fan and collector. Born in Brooklyn, New York, Brown served in the US Navy from 1956-1959 and worked as an engineer until 1975. In 1968 he co-founded Locus magazine and remained editor until his death in 2009. Brown also edited the fiction anthologies Alien Worlds (1976), Far Travellers (1976), and The Locus Awards (2004).
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Locus Science Fiction Foundatoin Archives were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Separated Materials
The Locus Science Fiction Foundation Archives are part of the Locus Science Fiction Foundation Collection. Print materials have been separated and are being cataloged individually. Search for "Locus Science Fiction Foundation" as author or keyword in the library catalog to find print materials from this collection.
Collection Overview
Collection includes names files for more than 800 people, many of whom are writers, editors, or publishers. The files contain correspondence, clippings, obituaries, and writings, the bulk of which relate to American writers, though there are several files kept on writers and fans from across the world, including China, Japan, and Russia. Much of the correspndence is about publishing news, corrections, and deaths in the science-fiction, fantasy, and horror community. There are several well-known correspondents including: Poul Anderson, Isaac Asimov, Jim Baen, Ian and Betty Ballantine, Algis Budrys, Octavia E. Butler, Arthur C. Clarke, L. Sprague de Camp, Harlan Ellison, Robert Heinlein, Ursula K. Le Guin, Dean Koontz, Andre Alice Norton, James Tiptree, Jr. (Alice Sheldon), and Gene Wolfe.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audio materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to request the production of listening copies.
Science fiction, American -- 20th century; Science fiction, American -- Correspondence; Science fiction, American -- Periodicals; Science fiction, Chinese -- 20th century; Science fiction, Russian -- 20th century; Science fiction, Japanese -- 20th century; Science fiction fans; Fantasy fiction; Horror tales -- 20th century; Oakland (Calif.); New York (State); Locus (Cambridge, Mass.); Locus Science Fiction Foundation; Brown, Charles N., 1937-2009; Meskys, Ed, 1936-; David, Vanderwerf, 1944-; Jones, Marsha Elkin; Benatan, Dena Carol; Anderson, Poul, 1926-2001; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992; Baen, Jim; Ballantine, Ian, 1916-1995; Ballantine, Betty, 1919-; Budrys, Algis, 1931-2008; Butler, Octavia E.; Clarke, Arthur C., 1917-2008; De Camp, L. Sprague, 1907-2000; Ellison, Harlan; Heinlein, Robert A., 1907-1988; Le Guin, Ursula K., 1929-2018; Koontz, Dean R., 1945-; Norton, Andre; Sheldon, Alice Bradley, 1915-1987; Tiptree, James, Jr., 1915-1987; Wolfe, Gene
- Name Files
  - Abe, Kobe, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Clippings
  - Ackerman, Forrest J, 1978-2008; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Correspondence, clippings, interviews, auction information, articles
  - Ackerman, Wendayne, 1990 (Box 1)
    Obituary
  - Ackroy, Peter, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Douglas, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Richard, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
    Clippings, promotional material
  - Adlard, Mark, undated (Box 1)
    Printed photograph with small biographical description.
  - Aiken, Joan, 1983-1998 (Box 1)
    Promotional materials
  - D'Ailleurs, Maison, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    Correspondence from Pascal Ducommun, pamphlet about Maison D'ailleurs: Musee de L'Utopie, des Voyages Extraordinaires et de la Science-Fiction
  - Albania, SF in, 1991 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, article
  - Aldiss, Brian, 1975-1995 (Box 1)
    Correspondence
  - Aldiss, Brian, 1982-1995 (Box 1)
    Clippings, articles, interviews
  - Aldrin, Buzz, 2000 (Box 1)
    Flyer for "The Return"
  - Alexander, David M., undated (Box 1)
    Book cover for "Fane"
  - Amis, Martin, 1990 (Box 1)
    Biography entry from "Current Biography"
  - "Analog" 50th Anniversary, 1980 (Box 1)
    Press release and cover proof of "Analog"
  - Anderson, Jack, undated (Box 1)
    Excerpt from book catalog
  - Anderson, Kevin, 1989-2003 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Poul, 1972-2001 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, funeral program
  - Andersson, C. Dean and Nina (A.K.A. Asa Drake and Jane Archer), 1987 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Arlan, 1987-1993 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, list of works
  - Anthony, Patricia, 1998 (Box 1)
    "Dallas Observer" Profile
  - Anthony, Piers, 1968-1991 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, clippings, photographic negatives, promotional materials, newsletters, book sales Statements
  - Anscombe, Roderick, 1994 (Box 1)
    Interview
  - Applebaum, Irwyn, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Arbour, Dennis, 1995 (Box 1)
    Profile in "The Republican Journal"
  - Asaro, Catherine, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
    Promotional materials, clippings, bibliography
  - Ashley, Mike, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Asimov, Isaac, 1970-1993 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, obituaries written for Locus, clippings, interviews, FBI files in response to a FOIA request
  - Askergren, Pierce, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Attanasio, Al, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Atwood, Margaret, 2005 (Box 1)
    "The Novels I Won't Write Soon" article
  - Auel, Jean, 1981-1991 (Box 1)
    Biography entry from "Current Biography," promotional materials, brief correspondence
  - Aurora Anthologies, 1980 (Box 1)
    "Final Report on Aurora Anthologies"
  - Auster, Paul, 1995 (Box 1)
    Clipping
  - Austin, Alicia, 1984 (Box 1)
    Brief correspondence
  - Avallone, Michael, 1994 (Box 1)
    Brief correspondence, profile, interview, resume, "Pulpcon Number 23, Just the Place for You and Me" article
  - Baen, Jim, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    Correspondence and press release regarding Baen Books
  - Bailey, Clayton, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Oversize-folder 1)
    "Robot Builder's Manual," "Robot Sculptures," "Science Fiction Sculpture..." catalog, profiles, brief correspondence
  - Baker, Kage, undated (Box 1)
    Biographical statement
  - Ballantine, Ian, 1977-1995; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Correspondence, profiles, business news, remembrances
  - Ballantine, Betty, 1992-1999 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, birthday booklet of letters from colleagues, publication announcement
  - Ballard, J.G., 1982-2008 (Box 1)
    Clippings, newsletters, biography from "Current Biography"
  - Banks, Iain, 1987-1996 (Box 1)
    Clippings, reviews
  - Banks, Lynne Reid, 1989 (Box 1)
    Clippings, promotional materials
  - Bantock, Nick, 1994 (Box 1)
    Interview clipping
  - Barker, Clive, 2001-2002, undated (Box 1)
    Clippings, profiles, interviews, promotional materials
  - Barks, Carl, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Barlowe, Wayne, 1983 (Box 1)
    Promotional materials, photographs of action figures
  - Barnes, Stevan, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Barr, George, 1979 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one letter)
  - Barrett, Neil, Jr., 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    Contact information, list of works
  - Baudino, Gael, undated (Box 1)
    Cover for "O Greenest Branch!"
  - Baxter, Stephen, 1994 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one letter), article by Baxter
  - Beagle, Peter, undated (Box 1)
    Profile in "Twentieth-Century American Literature"
  - Beamer, Charles, undated (Box 1)
    Profile in "Beyond: a Science Fiction/Fantasy Newsletter"
  - Bear, Astrid Anderson, 1972-1994 (Box 1)
    Six photographs
  - Bear, Greg, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Beason, Doug, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Belden, David, 1986 (Box 1)
    Press release for "Children of Arable"
  - Benatan, Dena, 1981-2009 (Box 1)
  - Benford, Greg, 1979-1989 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, clippings, articles, programs from conferences, travel notes, "Mozart on Morphine" draft, "Cobblestones into Highways" draft, "Evasions in SF" draft.
  - Bennett, Gary L., 1980 (Box 1)
    Reviews
  - Berkley, Miriam, 1987 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one letter), business card
  - Bertin, Eddy, 1980 (Box 1)
    Letter to the editor "Stayin' Alive by Writing SF Which is Not in English Language? You Can't!"
  - Bertram, Hal, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bester, Alfred, undated (Box 1)
    Remembrance of Alfred Bester by Charles Platt
  - Bishop, Michael, 1979-1986 (Box 1)
  - Bisson, Terry, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Bixby, Jerome, 1991 (Box 1)
    Profile in "Starlog"
  - Blassingame, Lurton, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Bleiler, E. F., 1978-1986 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one letter), "Publishers Weekly" interview
  - Blish, James and Judy, 1967-1981 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (two brief letters)
  - Bloch, Robert, 1972-1979 (Box 1)
    Clippings, correspondence (one letter)
  - Bogdanov, Alexander, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Bohnhoff, Maya Kaathryn, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one letter), profile in "Starlog"
  - Bonanno, Margaret Warden, 1992 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one brief letter)
  - Bond, Nelson, undated (Box 1)
    Contact information
  - Bonestell, Chesley, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
    Obituary, press release, clippings
  - Bordes, Francois (Carsac, Francis), 1981 (Box 1)
    Obituaries
  - Borges, Jorge Luis, 1979-1986 (Box 1)
  - Borgo Press, 1982 (Box 1)
    Catalog
  - Bosse, Malcolm, 1983 (Box 1)
    Publicity materials
  - Bova, Ben, 1980-1987 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, autobiography draft, "Building a Real World" (Philcon 80 Guest of Honor Speech) draft, clipping.
  - Bowes, Rick, 2000 (Box 1)
    "Locus Online" printout
  - Boyett, Steve, 1988 (Box 1)
    Newsletter
  - Boyle, T. C., 1991 (Box 1)
    Entry from "Current Biography"
  - Bradbury, Ray, 1980-2008 (Box 1)
    Clippings, playbill, reviews, interviews.
  - Bradfield, Scott, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, Marion Zimmer, 1977-1999 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, obituaries, reviews
  - Brandewyne, Rebecca, 1988 (Box 1)
    Publicity materials for "Passion Moon Rising," resume
  - Bretnor, Reginald, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Birdwell, Nelson E., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Brin, David, 1981-2001 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, promotional materials, travel notes
  - Briney, Robert, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Brite, Poppy Z., 1995 (Box 1)
    Interview in Mondo 2000
  - Broxon, Mildred Downey, 1981 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (brief letter), clipping
  - Brown, Charles N., 1966-2009 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, obituary, articles, article drafts, short biography, "Locus" August 2009 cover, travel information for Science Fiction tour of U.S.S.R., postcards with photographs
  - Brown, Christopher, 2017 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Howard, 2018 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Jerry, 1981 (Box 1)
    Press info sheet
  - Brunner, John, 1980-1986 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, photocopy of photograph
  - Brush, Karen, 1987 (Box 1)
    Promotional materials for "The Pig, the Prince and the Unicorn"
  - Brust, Steven, undated (Box 1)
    "The Cool Theory of Literature" draft
  - Bryant, Edward, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Buck, Doris Pitkin, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Budrys, Algis, 1977-1989 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, interview, "On Writing" column drafts, photograph
  - Bujor, Flavia, 2004 (Box 1)
    Printed out news article
  - Bukato, Wiktor, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Bulychev, Kyrill, 1977-1999 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, "Everything Still Ahead (Soviet SF in the Era of Glasnost'" draft, press release, clipping
  - Bulgaria, SF in, 1991 (Box 1)
    "SF in Bulgaria" draft by Dr. Julian Stoinove
  - Bunch, Chris, 1995-2005 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one email), article in Locus
  - Burgess, Anthony, 1984 (Box 1)
    Review in "Time" magazine
  - Burns, Jim, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    Illustrated book covers
  - Burriston, Donna, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Burroughs, Edgar Rice, 2003 (Box 1)
    "Burroughs Bulletin: Tarzan and the Lion Man" journal
  - Burroughs, William S., 1984-1997 (Box 1)
  - Busby, F. M., 1980-1983 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (two letters)
  - Butler, Bill, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Butler, Octavia, 1979-2006 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (four brief letters), obituaries, interviews, profiles
  - Byers, Edward, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Byron Preiss Visual Publications, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Cabana Boys, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Caceck, P. D., 1951, undated (Box 1)
    Holiday card, birth certificate
  - Cady, Jack, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Calder, Richard, 2005 (Box 1)
    "Spark in the Background Noise, The Rebel with a Clue: an Interview with Richard Calder"
  - Calvino, Italo, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Campbell, John W., 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    Correspondence regarding publication of Campbell's letters. Most of the letters are to and from Michael D. Glyer.
  - Campbell, Ramsey, 1981 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one brief letter), copy of "Loveman's Comeback" short story
  - Card, Orson Scott, 1979-2000 (Box 1)
    Correspondence (one letter), interviews, profiles, reviews
  - Carey, Jacqueline, 2001 (Box 1)
    Pamphlet about "Kushiel's Dart"
  - Carey, Peter, 1986-1991 (Box 1)
  - Carr, John F., 1981 (Box 1)
    Press release
  - Carr, Terry, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Carrol, Jonathan, 1989-2002 (Box 2)
    Profiles, reviews, clippings
  - Carter, Angela, 1980-2007 (Box 2)
    Clippings, reviews, obituary
  - Cartier, Edd, 1998-2004 (Box 2)
    Interview, clippings, promotional materials
  - Cartmill, Cleve, 2001-2002 (Box 2)
    FOIA documents relating to Cartmill's short story "Deadline," includes copy of story
  - Carver, Jeff, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    Birth announcement with photograph, clippings
  - Cave, Hugh, 2003 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (brief email from Milt Thomas)
  - Chabon, Michael, 2002 (Box 2)
    Profile in "Pages"
  - Chalker, Mirage Press, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Chalker, Jack, 1982-1989 (Box 2)
  - Chandler, Bertram A., undated (Box 2)
  - Charteris, Leslie, 1993 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter) written by Ian Dickerson correcting the obituary of Charteris in Locus
  - Cherryh, C. J., 1979-1983 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (two brief letters), clippings, profiles
  - Chizmar, Richard, 1999 (Box 2)
    Book jacket, Locus profile
  - Chopra, Deepak, 1995 (Box 2)
    "Publishers Weekly" interview
  - Christopher, John, 1985-1991 (Box 2)
    Photographic negatives, profile in "Million" magazine
  - Claresan, Thomas, 1990 (Box 2)
    Profile in "Boskone XXIV Program Book"
  - Clarke, Arthur C., 1977-2008; 5 folders (Box 2)
    Correspondence, clippings, programs, list of works
  - Coblentz, Stanton (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter), bio, brief obituary
  - Cogswell, George, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Collins, Nancy, 1990-1999 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter, one greeting card, one email)
  - Compton, Dan, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Morton N., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Coney, Michael, 2005 (Box 2)
    Clippings, including obituary
  - Connor, Jeff, 1985 (Box 2)
    Article in "Scream/Press/Release" newsletter
  - Constantine, Storm, 1988 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (letter from John Jarrold, editor at Futura), description of the concept of Wraeththu
  - Cook, Paul, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Cooke, Peyton, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Cooper, Louise, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Cooper, Susan, undated (Box 2)
    Reading announcement
  - Cornwell, Bernard, 1996 (Box 2)
    "Publishers Weekly" profile
  - Cornwell, Patricia, 2007 (Box 2)
    Book cover for "Book of the Dead"
  - Cory and Collins, 1983 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter from Paul J. Stevens)
  - De La Concha, Raquel, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Coover, Robert, 1991 (Box 2)
    Biographical entry in "Current Biography"
  - Corwin, Norman, 1999 (Box 2)
    Article by Ray Bradbury about Norman Cowin in "Westways Southern California's Lifestyle Magazine"
  - Grimwood, Jon Courtenay, undated (Box 2)
    Bio
  - Coville, Bruce, undated (Box 2)
    Profile in "Boskone 45 Souvenir Book"
  - Cowper, Richard (A.K.A. John Middleton Murry, Jr.), 1981 (Box 2)
  - Crabbe, Buster, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Craft, Kinuko, 1981 (Box 2)
    Profile in "Communication Arts"
  - Crais, Robert, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Cramer, Kathryn, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Crawford, William, 1977-1984 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter from Peggy Crawford), one photograph
  - Crayne, Chuck, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Crichton, Michael, 1985-1999 (Box 2)
  - Crossen, Kendall, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Cuddy, Page, undated (Box 2)
  - Culiano, Ioan, 1991 (Box 2)
    Clipping about Culiano's murder
  - Cumello, Charles, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Curtis, Richard, 1981-1987 (Box 2)
    Correspondence, two photographs, legal complaint against John Schaffner Agency and Patrick Delahunt
  - Curtis/Delahunt Case, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
    Correspondence, legal documents
  - Dacruz, Daniel, undated (Box 2)
  - D'Adamo, Allegra, 1984 (Box 2)
    Promotion announcement in "Publishers Weekly"
  - Dahl, Roald, 1986-2013 (Box 2)
    Article in "Publishers Weekly"
  - Dalmas, John, 1985 (Box 2)
    Book cover for "The Walkaway Clause"
  - Dann, Jack, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Dark Forces, 1981 (Box 2)
    Book cover for "Dark Forces: New Stories of Suspense and Supernatural Horror..."
  - Darnay, Arsen, 1978 (Box 2)
    "Boskone 15" announcement
  - Dart-Thornton, Cecilia, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Datlow, Ellen, undated (Box 2)
    "The Year in Horror--Partial Summary" manuscript draft
  - Davidson, Avram, 1979-1993 (Box 2)
  - Davies, Dick, undated (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one brief letter), sample of artwork
  - Davies, Robertson, undated (Box 2)
    Photograph clipped from promotional materials
  - Davis, Grania/Steve, 1980 (Box 2)
    Correspondence, travel notes, one photograph, clipping
  - De Bolt, Joe, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (three letters)
  - De Camp, L. Sprague, 1973-190 (Box 2)
  - Dedecker, Sally, 1987 (Box 2)
    Group photograph in "Publishers Weekly"
  - Deighton, Len, 1986 (Box 2)
    Ad in "The Bookseller"
  - Delany, Samuel, 1967-1999 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one brief letter), clippings, "Stars in My Pocket Like Grains of Sand" book jacket, film prospectus for "Atlantis and Other New York Tales"
  - Delaney, Joseph, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Del Rey, Judy Lynn, 1980-1986 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter), several obituaries written by authors (including Isaac Asimov), press release regarding promotion at Ballantine Books
  - Del Rey, Lester, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Delillo, Don, 1988 (Box 2)
    Review in "Publishers Weekly"
  - De Pedrolo, Manuel, 1990 (Box 2)
    Obituary written by Juan Carlos Planells
  - Derleth, August, 1973 (Box 2)
    Renunciation by Donald Wandrei of the Right of First Option to Buy Arkham House
  - DeVet, Charles, 1992-1997 (Box 2)
    Obituary, award announcement
  - Diaz, Junot, 2012 (Box 2)
    Profile in "Publishers Weekly"
  - Dibell, Ansen, 1982 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (brief letter)
  - Dick, Tessa, 1983-1988 (Box 2)
  - Dick, Philip K., 1972-2007; 4 folders (Box 2)
    Correspondence (two letters), clippings, obituaries and eulogies from many writers (including a letter from Ursula Le Guin), FOIA records,
  - Dickinson, Peter, 1984-1988 (Box 2)
  - Dickson, Gordon R., 1979-1990 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (four brief letters), photograph, unused cover for "The Final Encyclopedia"
  - Di Fate, Vincent, 1978-1994 (Box 2)
  - Di Filippo, Paul, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Dillon, Diane and Leo, 1976-2000 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one brief letter), photographs, profile in "Graphics Today"
  - Disch, Thomas M., 1979-1995 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (four brief letters), clippings
  - Doctorow, Cory, undated (Box 2)
    "I, Robot" discussion draft
  - Doctorow, E. L., 2004-2006 (Box 2)
  - Doherty, Barbara and Tom, 1985-2012 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one brief letter and email), clipping
  - Donning, 1985 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (two letters ), newsletters, press releases
  - Donohue, Keith, 2006-2007 (Box 2)
  - Donaldson, Stephen, 1980-1992 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter), clippings, wikipedia printout, article drafts
  - Dorsey, Candas Jane, 2000 (Box 2)
    Printout from professional website
  - Doroschenko, Leo, undated (Box 2)
  - Douglas, Carol Nelson, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (two letters), cover for "Six of Swords," copy of newsletter from Apple Computer Dealers
  - Douglas, John, 1995 (Box 2)
    Resume
  - Duane, Diane, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Drake, Asa, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Ducornet, Rikki, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Duncan, Dave, undated (Box 2)
    Profile in "Beyond"
  - Duncan, David, undated (Box 2)
  - Dunn, J. R., 1997 (Box 2)
    Page from book catalog
  - Dunn, Katharine, 1989 (Box 2)
    Pamphlet about "Geek Love"
  - Dutton, Syd, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Dystel, Oscar, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Eco, Umberto, 1989 (Box 2)
    Interview in "Publishers Weekly"
  - Eddings, David, undated (Box 2)
  - Edelman, Scott, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Effinger, George Alec (Piglet), 1989-2002 (Box 2)
    Correspondence (one letter), obituary, bios
  - Egan, Greg, 1997 (Box 2)
    Bibliography
  - Eiser, Will, 1946-1955 (Box 2)
    Printed-out artwork
  - Easton, Tom, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Elgin, Suzette Haden, undated (Box 2)
    Partial Minicon 31 program
  - Elliott, Tom, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Ellison, Harlan, 1952-2014; two folders (Box 2)
    Correspondence, book covers, legal documents, promotional materials, newsletters
  - Elwood, Roger P., 1977 (Box 2)
  - Eschbach, Lloyd, 1981-1992 (Box 2)
  - Evans, William Harrington, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Farmer, Philip Jose, 1977-2009 (Box 2)
    Correspondence, printed-out articles about Farmer
  - Farsace, Larry, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Faust, Joe Clifford, undated (Box 3)
  - Feck, Lou, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Fforde, Jasper, 2002 (Box 3)
    Review in "The New York Times"
  - Fiedler, Leslie, 1991 (Box 3)